<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-01-05T11:00:44+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><entry><title type="html">Happy 2025</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2025/01/02/happy-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy 2025"/><published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2025/01/02/happy-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2025/01/02/happy-2025.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="a-look-back-at-2024">A look back at 2024</h2> <p>2024 was a fairly eventful year all things considered on the professional front:</p> <ol> <li>I finally became a professional investor on the buy side</li> <li>Learned a lot about what actually goes into doing due diligence on a business</li> <li>Tried my hand at Private Equity with some of the <a href="https://chryscapital.com/people/">best people in the business</a></li> <li>Very quickly realized I would be terrible in a hierarchical environment regardless of whether it was IB or PE and did course correction (i.e. quit a job that could have set me up for millions)</li> <li>Moved to Singapore to work for a Hedge Fund covering Indian Equities!</li> </ol> <p>Honestly if you asked me, the day I ended up in B-School if my life would end up here, I would have laughed you out of the room. Life works in funny ways! xD</p> <h2 id="what-do-i-not-want-to-change-in-2025">What do I not want to change in 2025?</h2> <p>Touchwood!</p> <p><img src="_attachments/Pasted image 20250102201511.png" alt="Meme"/></p> <ol> <li>My work-life balance has been in the best possible shape over a period of a gruelling last 6 years since undergrad. I am very grateful that it has turned for the better and I wish to keep it this way.</li> <li>I like living in Singapore and would want to at least spend the rest of 2025 here. The city is beautiful and I am yet to <a href="https://guide.michelin.com/sg/en/singapore-region/singapore/restaurants">explore</a> so much of the <a href="https://guide.michelin.com/sg/en/article/travel/must-try-hawker-food-in-singapore">food scene</a> that the place has to offer!</li> <li>I recently made the trip back to India after a 2.5 month stay in SG for one of my best friend’s wedding. I do still miss being around my parents and some of my closest friends in Mumbai. I hope I can keep making such trips every 1-2 months!</li> </ol> <h2 id="what-do-i-want-to-achieve-in-2025">What do I want to achieve in 2025?</h2> <p>Yes, these are what are also called resolutions</p> <p><img src="_attachments/Pasted image 20250102201629.png" alt="Meme"/></p> <ol> <li> <p><strong><em>Health:</em></strong> I want to be in a better shape. That is going to be my top priority for the year, hopefully I will go back to how thin I was in insti. I want to go from being fat and ugly to only ugly.</p> <p>\(\rightarrow\) Will track regularly using Strava - make sure I get an hour of exercise in on a daily basis till my weight comes down</p> </li> <li> <p><strong><em>Code:</em></strong> Write more code this year vs 2020-24 combined. I used to be a decent software engineer eons ago but that skill has started to rust. Goal here is to make sure I push atleast a 100 lines of code every week to my Github.</p> <p>\(\rightarrow\) Will track regularly using Github / Obsidian</p> </li> <li> <p><strong><em>Social:</em></strong> Now that I have moved to a different country, I am pretty worried about how much my social life back in India is dwindling. To course correct, I plan to call atleast one person (my parents don’t count) who lives far away on weekends.</p> <p>\(\rightarrow\) Will track using Obsidian</p> </li> <li> <p><strong><em>Investing:</em></strong> I’m finally in a job where I can work on building theses directly on individual stocks (rather than private businesses which are hard to track post a deal if missed). Goal here is to build a coverage set of 20-25 names that I have a complete handle on.</p> <p>\(\rightarrow\) For long I’ve wanted to look into Capital Goods, Healthcare, IT/Internet, and Retail names when I worked in public equities. Track using office tools at work.</p> </li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A look back at 2024]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moving my page and blog to Jekyll</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2024/11/30/moving-my-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moving my page and blog to Jekyll"/><published>2024-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2024/11/30/moving-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2024/11/30/moving-my-blog.html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been putting off moving my page and blog to Jekyll for a long time. Finally, I have done it! I’ll keep posting on Substack but this will be my primary blog going forward.</p> <p>We are in the era of Web 3.0 where the ownership of content should be with the creator. To that end, as a HODLer, its only natural that I walk the talk.</p> <p>See you around!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="update"/><category term="blog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been putting off moving my page and blog to Jekyll for a long time. Finally, I have done it! I’ll keep posting on Substack but this will be my primary blog going forward.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Older but none the wiser…</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2024/01/01/ashutosh-jha-older-but-none-the-wiser.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Older but none the wiser…"/><published>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2024/01/01/ashutosh-jha-older-but-none-the-wiser</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2024/01/01/ashutosh-jha-older-but-none-the-wiser.html"><![CDATA[<p>Let’s start out with the happy parts of the post first - a very happy new year to everyone!</p> <p><strong>I’ve turned 27 (oh no.)</strong></p> <p>I’ve come to that age in my life where I’m not exactly very old but I can’t call myself young anymore (27 is really weird!) - I don’t get the TikTok / Reels generation, but I enjoy doomscrolling on Twitter as much as I did in undergrad. I hate clubbing but will occasionally enjoy the nightout with the right friends partying. Paradoxical in every sense of the word.</p> <p>Everyone from BSchool and Undergrad are getting married and having kids, while I’m the kid in my life. The irony is not wasted on me!</p> <p><strong>I’ve called it quits on Investment Banking</strong></p> <p>On a personal news front, the biggest development this year has been to get out of Investment Banking and into Private Equity. While everyone was cribbing about 70 hr weeks on Twitter, I was smirking at the normies who haven’t ever done multiple weeks of 18 hr days, 7 days a week (~100-120 hr weeks).<br/> <br/></p> <p align="center"> <img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fe5f92668-a603-4f05-bca7-3b843220d907_750x731.jpeg" width="50%"/> </p> <center>Truth of corporate life</center> <p><br/></p> <p>While I have no problems with 70 hr weeks, 100+ hrs has an impact on life that is only visible on the weighing scale (I put on 15kgs in my time at IB :) )</p> <p>On the terms of blame, I blame the industry altogether and no particular bank. It is very clearly a commoditized industry atleast at a junior level (commodity being analyst labour), differentiation as a result is much hard and folks try all sorts of bending backwards with “visibility” and “optics” at work (god only knows what that means!)</p> <p><strong>Investing is hard</strong></p> <p>I had to make the hard choice of actually going for a PhD or staying back in India for the long term. Continuing in IB was a clear no go because of the work-life imbalance implications on my health. The choice was made for me due to a personal need of being close to my parents, and I thus ended up in Private Equity. It’s been only a couple of months but what’s very obvious is that this is hard.</p> <p>Not hard in terms of hours put in, but intellectually hard. Constantly being aware of my biases and having them pointed out in investment committee presentations is not as fun as people make it out to be.</p> <p>The fun part of the job is however in the reading and learning bit. I get to sit and read for a living, do armchair thinking, work with incredible promoters, and get paid for doing what I love.</p> <p>The people are crazy smart - Kunal and Sanjay particularly - are amongst the smartest people I’ve had a chance to learn from. More importantly, they are really nice people to work with and have wholesome lives outside work and no air of arrogance. All I can say is that I’ve been really lucky to have a chance to work with such people.</p> <p><strong>What I plan to do better in 2024</strong></p> <p align="center"> <img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F50543f3d-fcec-458d-8cc6-183f0f49b87e_400x508.jpeg" width="30%"/> </p> <center>Calvin and Hobbes teaches more about life than any self-help book</center> <p><br/></p> <p>A new year by its very social construct nature, gives us a chance for a clean slate, a fresh start. I hope I’m able to make the best of it in some of these areas in this order:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Health</strong> - I’ve thankfully already started the reversal in the damage that my messed up work hours brought about; Goal is to make progress towards getting off my arse and move around more in some form. Hopefully I enter 2025 in better shape.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Investing</strong> - I’m a dumb dumb as far as investing is concerned. I want to expand my circle of competence to Healthcare and Financial Institutions over this year. Best way to do this would be to be an apprentice to the people who know how to do it at my workplace</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Social</strong> - Get back in touch with my friends again now that there is some semblence of boundaries with work. I want to spend more time listening to the boys (particularly Rava) drop politically incorrect statements, go on atleast one vacation trip with the boys, and spend more time with my loved ones.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Learn how to drive</strong> - As insignificant as this sounds, I want my driver’s license for 4 wheelers. I’ve relied on Ubers long enough but now I’d really like to try driving myself for a bit.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Blog regularly -</strong> This post comes after an 8 month break on this substack. I’ll try to do a post a month (at most 2 months for margin of safety!) and keep</p> </li> </ol> <p>Hopefully I’ll do atleast some of these going ahead. Chances are I’ll do none. But, the goal is to build in the bull case systems where I do all of it. God only knows what will happen, I’ve always been bad at predictions!</p> <p>Till next time!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s start out with the happy parts of the post first - a very happy new year to everyone!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Survival</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2023/04/17/ashutosh-jha-survival.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Survival"/><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2023/04/17/ashutosh-jha-survival</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2023/04/17/ashutosh-jha-survival.html"><![CDATA[<p>As a first year at IIM Ahmedabad, I was given a single piece of advice that carried me through the first year - “Survive, the rest will follow”.</p> <p>(Interestingly enough, once you finish first year you’re given a <em>PGP1 Survivor</em> T-shirt)</p> <p>Ajit Jain of Berkshire - a terrific capital allocator - answered this as his response to what he thinks about - <a href="https://buggyhuman.substack.com/p/i-hope-i-havent-done-anything-stupid">“I hope I haven’t done anything stupid today”</a></p> <p>The first thing that Pulak Prasad’s <a href="https://www.amazon.in/What-Learned-About-Investing-Darwin-ebook/dp/B0BG99WS31">brilliant book</a> covers in their philosophy is exactly this - the ability to avoid self-goals is the most important thing.</p> <p>As a clueless human, while it’s good to be curious, I would rather avoid the fate that my feline friend suffered. The trick is to constantly tell myself that I’m clueless.</p> <p>In every class with teacher during investing, he would teach us something and give an example of a real life stonk with some context. He would then ask us to take a position in the stonk at a point in history showing us a rosy picture that he painted. When most of the class was done taking a long position, he would fast forward to the future and show us how we would lose money.</p> <p>Now I’m not sure if this is what teacher intended but I took away a single lesson from this, start with the position that you’re going to get screwed. Find out what it is that will screw you. And if there is anything that is going to screw you completely (-90%+ loss), avoid it.</p> <p>This stance of avoiding ruin works, and boy it works really well simply because of the fact that the prior distribution of the stock market is that there are really very few companies that are worth holding forever. So the strategy that tries to minimize false positives (i.e. I buy a crappy business) will win over the strategy that tries to minimize false negatives (i.e. I miss out on a great business). Again, Pulak’s book does a really good job of explaining it - go read!</p> <p>When sitting to analyse a business, I have started using a checklist to see if there is even one tickmark on the negative side - because if there is, I am better off avoiding it</p> <p>A non-exhaustive subset of the really important parts of the checklist for me at this point are:</p> <ol> <li> <p><strong>Is the promoter shady?</strong><br/> I remember talking to a pretty good public equities investor and asking him how he thinks of governance in mid-cap and small-cap stocks. He told me - <em>“Bhai dhandhe mein koi doodh ka dhula nahi hai” (No one is clean in the world of business)</em>. To his merit, this is actually true. But I want a business forever!! I will take a position only with a guy who is “doodh ka dhula”.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Is the management terrible at capital allocation?</strong><br/> The pathway to hell is paved with good intentions. Even if the promoter isn’t shady, I don’t want to be suckered into a business where the promoter/management can’t allocate capital well. Historical evidence of expanding into random business segments, showy M&amp;As (yes I sound like a hypocrite given I’m an i-banker but it’s because I’m one I know it’s very hard to do it well), restructuring for family planning while shafting the minority shareholders, etc. are blaring alarms.</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Is there a voice in my head telling “This time will be different”?</strong><br/> The stupidest (and my first) stock I bought was by running into a sector which was known globally for terrible economics (think airlines, hotels, restaurants, etc.) but I was trying to pick a winner because it was thematic at the time. I hold that stock till date with a 70% loss. I look at it as fees paid to learn a lesson the hard way. Run away from themes, run away from the “new” approach to a hard economics business, and run away the moment I tell myself “This time will be different”</p> </li> <li> <p><strong>Turnaround stocks</strong><br/> This is the one that took me the longest time to put on the checklist. I used to think that I was really smart at spotting turnarounds (thanks to my ability of clearing entrance exams despite being a dumb-dumb). Again a lesson learned the hard way where I thought a company bringing on a new CTO would make it “digitally transformed”.<br/> Never again.<br/> Don’t get me wrong - turn arounds are the places where you can make a huge return. I still believe the quantum of return in special situations is much higher than traditional investing. <strong>I’m just really bad at spotting them correctly - hence I stay well away from them even when I think I’m relatively sure. (It’s a slippery slope to being relatively sure of every turnaround)</strong><br/> I would rather bet my money on what I know relatively well - understanding economics of an already well run business - than make a bet on a company turning around because of whatever reason (management, market, theme, I don’t care - pick your poison).</p> </li> </ol> <p>This brings me to the end of this topic on Survival. I’ll just leave you with good music.</p> <p>Alexa play <em>Stayin’ Alive</em> on Youtube:</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="investing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As a first year at IIM Ahmedabad, I was given a single piece of advice that carried me through the first year - “Survive, the rest will follow”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Invert, always Invert!</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/11/26/ashutosh-jha-invert-always-invert.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Invert, always Invert!"/><published>2022-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2022/11/26/ashutosh-jha-invert-always-invert</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/11/26/ashutosh-jha-invert-always-invert.html"><![CDATA[<p>One of my favourite pieces of advice that I’ve read is from Ajit Jain on how he constantly thinks: <strong>“I hope I have not done anything stupid today”</strong></p> <p>The more I see investing from a student’s lens, the more I realize how important this is. Choosing what <strong>not to do</strong> is far more important that choosing what to do.</p> <p>As I think more about it, this line of advice has given me a lot more clarity in the chaotic world of markets around me. There are some obvious ones that I can get out of the way:</p> <ul> <li> <p><em>Don’t touch businesses I don’t fully understand</em><br/> <br/> <strong>Corollary:</strong> Be honest to myself about if I really understand it through Feynman’s ELI5 approach<br/> <br/> <strong>Result</strong> : I’ve stayed away from sectors like Banks, Pharmaceuticals, Real Estate. Focused mostly on pure tech or tech enabled sectors, consumer and retail, industrial goods.</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Macro predictions make no sense in a long term world</em><br/> <br/> <strong>Corollary:</strong> Stay away from technical analysis, and other forms of quantitative driven investing. Although I like to think my centum in math from 8th standard means something, there are folks much better than I am (Citadel and RenTech have teams of Math/Physics PhDs) at short term forecasting. Plus in the long term macro always mean reverts.<br/> <br/> <strong>Result:</strong> I don’t want my investments to be driven by timing of entry and exit. I would rather invest in pockets where I know a good company can continue compounding and be a monopolistic business in an attractive industry. So much so that valuation is at best cherry on the cake, not the cake itself.</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Stick to historically proven instances of management execution not stories of the future.</em><br/> <br/> <strong>Corollary:</strong> Switch your brain off when management cooks khayali pulao. Stay away from buzzwords. Read a lot more transcripts and annual reports than talking to management as of now.<br/> <br/> <strong>Result:</strong> A lot of my time goes in highlighting notes from ConCalls on what management has said and then going to next year’s annual reports to see if that’s what they actually do. Keeps me sane, sticks me to a process, and reduces the fuzziness in assessing buggy humans.</p> </li> <li> <p><em>Don’t buy at any price</em> <br/> <br/> <strong>Corollary:</strong> As of now, I don’t even look at businesses above a certain P/E. Unlike most value folks, I’m open to that number changing for a very high growth company. But but, I’m a skeptic since I’ve only seen less than 5 businesses who have maintained high growth historically to warrant such multiples.<br/> <br/> <strong>Result:</strong> Use valuation as a test for whether to buy or not always. Buy at any price is a flawed philosophy in my brain.</p> </li> </ul> <hr/> <p>A lot of what I’ve laid out may (and most probably will!) change as I learn more about investing.</p> <p>I might get into other sectors because I spend enough time studying them to finally understand them (enough time &gt;= 3 months of deep work!).</p> <p>The one on predictions might change if and only if I return to being a quant and spend north of 5 years learning how to do short term predictions well enough. But as I was telling a friend, I just like the fundamental long term approach a lot more because I’m way too lazy to take on the stress of regularly monitoring a systematic trading algo at all times of the day. We’ll see if this changes.</p> <p>I doubt the buy at any price bit will change but I am a little sold on the idea that great companies rarely are available for cheap anymore in India. Furthermore, there are instances where I have seen a super high growth company actually warrant very high multiples but it’s too hard to predict as far as I can tell and I’m better off just not doing it right now. Regardless, my way of screening using valuation might change.</p> <p>Most probably the thing that will change is me getting better at evaluating management to the point where I will rely more on reference checks as I build up my network but I don’t think I’ll give up on the leg work of finding historical instances of execution ability. I’m too paranoid to trust someone that blindly and will sleep peacefully at night knowing my trust is triangulated by historical proof.</p> <hr/> <p>I’m starting to love investing as a study a lot more. Everyday I get to learn something new and I get to make money by sitting and reading and doing scuttlebutt leg work.</p> <p>Life’s been fun so far in this line of work!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="investing"/><category term="mental models"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of my favourite pieces of advice that I’ve read is from Ajit Jain on how he constantly thinks: “I hope I have not done anything stupid today”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good Investing in Practice</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/08/24/ashutosh-jha-good-investing-in-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good Investing in Practice"/><published>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2022/08/24/ashutosh-jha-good-investing-in-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/08/24/ashutosh-jha-good-investing-in-practice.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-is-good-investing">What is good investing?</h1> <p>When I had started out (I’m still in my first steps in this world!) on my journey in Financial Markets, this question seemed like a very stupid one. After all, good investing was anything that made me money. Who cares how that came about — whether it was YOLOing on the latest shit coin, predicting macro shacro, claiming superior understanding of a few strokes of paintbrushes/ JPEG of an ape, drawing lines on a squiggly chart, or god forbid, picking stocks by studying underlying businesses.</p> <p>In hindsight, the definition for good investing for me has only changed slightly - Good Investing is still putting in money to get a lot more money back <em><strong>but without any chance of losing it all.</strong></em></p> <h2 id="watch-me-burn">Watch me burn!</h2> <p>“Duh!” was the response of my friends when I told them of the profound change in my definition. Obviously you never want to lose all your money when you’re looking for more money back. It’s so seemingly simple but then again, extremely hard to put to practice. You don’t even need to look too far away to see this, just log on to r/wallstreetbets.</p> <p>While dissing on the degenerates at WSB is easy, us sophisticated types are just hiding behind the veil of sophistication to hide our degeneracy. A non-exhaustive list of examples of this include:</p> <ul> <li> <p>Using heuristics like RSA, Support Levels, lines on a price chart without understanding hindsight bias.</p> </li> <li> <p>Trying to algorithmically trade without having the compute power or even the army of STEM PhDs with institutional investors</p> </li> <li> <p>Buying into Shitcoins because a 16yr old bought a lambo using those</p> </li> <li> <p>Using options without understanding how they truly work</p> </li> </ul> <h2 id="dont-beat-around-the-bush---what-is-good-investing-practically-then">Don’t beat around the bush - what is good investing practically then?</h2> <p>Good investing still rests on just three tenets as Ben Graham originally described:</p> <ol> <li> <p>Understanding that stocks represent businesses</p> </li> <li> <p>Having a margin of safety</p> </li> <li> <p>Not giving into the mood and momentum of the market (or Mr. Market)</p> </li> </ol> <p>Most seemingly simple things are hard to implement though, including but not limited to watching what you eat to lose weight, just being yourself in social situations, and not binging on a full season of How I Met Your Mother to get enough sleep.</p> <p>On Margin of Safety, always, always have a margin of safety beyond the intrinsic value for a business. Always start with the basic underlying fact that you are and will always be a buggy idiotic human being. You will miss out on some piece of information regardless of what you do and the cushion for your stupidity is the margin of safety. Growing up with a father from the <a href="https://buggyhuman.substack.com/p/a-tale-of-two-generations">“miss” generation</a> who just put money in FDs and Post Office savings accounts, extreme risk aversion was my first financial advice. In fact, it has caused me good pain where I regularly undervalue stuff till a <em><strong>real</strong></em> buying opportunity presents itself. I would rather miss buying on the good stuff than artificially lowering my margin because I will necessarily get addicted to lowering it even further down the line.</p> <p>On Stocks as businesses, curiosity coupled with intellectual honesty is the source of competitive advantage. There are two parts to this:</p> <ol> <li> <p>First, be genuinely curious about how every piece of the business works till you can explain it to a 5 yr old. Do the homework, talk to people inside, and outside the business. Use your judgement to figure out what could make a business have a moat with its customers.</p> </li> <li> <p>Second, be honest to yourself. Know what you know and know what you don’t. Stay away from things you don’t understand. Pick areas which you’re more comfortable with through your own expertise either through education or legitimate research. If you don’t understand something, don’t fool yourself into thinking you do.</p> </li> </ol> <p>On Mr. Market which arguably is the hardest of the three, stick to the north star of your investing framework. The woods of markets are real lovely, and real fckin deep. Keep reminding yourself to stick to picking good businesses and not get lost in the latest fad that’s running around. Trust me it’s super hard doing this — particularly when you read WSB and see a 16yr old turn an NFT for millions overnight. It is of paramount importance regardless. If you can’t do this, and most can’t, you’re just better off with the index.</p> <h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h2> <p>It’s been a fun journey so far in this world, but it’s good to keep reminding myself of what should my starting point be in any investment. For most part my index fund takes care of my money needs - if I am to however do investing myself for whatever reason, I atleast should do the good kind. I can always turn to Reddit for indulging my darker desires.</p>]]></content><author><name>Ashutosh Jha</name></author><category term="investing"/><category term="value investing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is good investing?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learnings from IIM Ahmedabad</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/03/08/ashutosh-jha-learnings-from-iim-ahmedabad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learnings from IIM Ahmedabad"/><published>2022-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2022/03/08/ashutosh-jha-learnings-from-iim-ahmedabad</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/03/08/ashutosh-jha-learnings-from-iim-ahmedabad.html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s nearly 3 AM in the night, and I’m at Vikram Sarabhai Library because the heat in the old campus is getting intolerable. As I enter the last week or so in my MBA journey, I think it’s an excellent time to take a step back and look at the bigger picture.</p> <p>IIM Ahmedabad (or WIMWI as it is more fondly called) has an exciting curriculum and pedagogy, which, as far as I know, is one of a kind even in BSchools outside India.</p> <p>There are no teaching based courses at IIMA - all courses follow a case pedagogy where students are expected to read and analyse real world business cases and the class acts more like a discussion forum for the instructor to bring out the learnings in. What this translates to is a lot of effort before each class in terms of prep itself.</p> <p>The first year (PGP1) is exceptionally packed with courses that give students no elective courses to pick. The pressure of juggling academics, summer placements, career clubs, and networking, in general, is truly astounding. A famous alumnus and ex-RBI governor famously noted that <em><strong>if you survive the first year at IIMA, you’ll survive almost anything else in your career</strong></em>.</p> <p>Once you survive PGP1, the second year (PGP2), on the other hand, is strikingly “free.” There are no compulsory courses to take; you get to pick electives as per your choice. Post the summer, about half the campus has a job in hand through PPOs, so the general enthu and FOMO for acads go down considerably.</p> <p>For my elective courses, I focused on picking courses majorly in the Economics and Finance Areas here at IIMA. Still, I was also able to squish in some classes in Operations, Strategy and, in fact, one course even in Marketing. This post will focus on courses I took in PGP2 since I felt those added the most value for my time here!</p> <p>I guess I’ve ranted for a long time about the system itself, so without any further ado, let’s begin a longer rant on my favorite courses at IIMA!</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Applied Value Investing by Prof. A.N. Seshadri</strong></p> <p>This was by far my favorite course at WIMWI - taken by a visiting faculty with a brilliant track record in Stock Investing at a Public Markets fund called Nalanda Capital. While the classes were 75 minutes long, Prof. Seshadri was kind enough to entertain questions from us well into 2 hrs and more at times. Just how much he cared about the students makes it my top course here.</p> <p><em><strong>Key Takeaway (culted shamelessly from Buggy Humans in a Messy World):</strong></em></p> <p>Intelligent investing rests on three tenets. Intrinsic business value. The margin of safety. Mr. Market. If we truly understand the essence of Ben Graham’s three tenets, we’re done. There’s nothing else to sensible investing. View stocks as businesses. Roughly gauge what it’s worth in the few cases where we can. Since the world is all messy and we’re all buggy, don’t cut it too fine. Keep some cushion. View nutty counterparties as entertainment unless they offer something actionable based on the above.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Alternative Investments by Prof. Jayanth Varma</strong></p> <p>It would be a crime not to mention a class by Prof. Jayanth Varma in my list of favorite courses. This was one of my favorite courses simply because of the wide variety of asset classes discussed in the course - including Currencies, Commodities, Art, Real Estate, Distressed Debt, and wait for it… <em><strong>Underwriting a Divorce Settlement.</strong></em></p> <p>Prof. Varma is super quippy and makes brilliant one-liners that stick. Plus, the guy is one of the most well-read and clear-minded people I’ve met in my life. A must-take class!</p> <p><em><strong>Key Takeaways (I only remember the one-liners, so I’ll dump some of them here)</strong></em></p> <p>(Context - Motives of a Financial Sponsor) Money in a battle takes no sides - it has only one color.</p> <p>(Context - Underwriting of Legal Proceedings) If you want to find out the actual net worth of a person, don’t hire an accountant; employ a divorce lawyer.</p> <p>(Context - Commodities Investing) Investing in commodities is basically a short position on Human Ingenuity.</p> <p>(Context - Cryptocurrency Bans) What do you think is harder to kill - a single blue whale or all the cockroaches in a city?</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Game Theory and Applications by Prof. Viswanath Pingali</strong></p> <p>Prof. Pingali is hands down one of the most entertaining professors here at IIMA. Despite having a non-attendance policy himself, I rarely saw people miss his classes. While I went into the class feeling it wouldn’t add much value, Prof. Pingali takes a more business-oriented view of Game Theory than a mathematical one.</p> <p><em><strong>Key Takeaway:</strong></em></p> <p>Human beings are irrational agents. However, humans, when aggregated into institutions, <em><strong>generally</strong></em> are rational. When working against other rational agents, rational agents will <em><strong>almost</strong></em> always lead to an equilibrium from which no agent will want to defect. In many cases, there are different types of agents, and when agents can’t reveal who they are directly (which is most of the time), they use signals that are costly to replicate to create separating equilibriums that show their type.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Elephants and Cheetahs by Prof. Saral Mukherjee</strong></p> <p>Strategy courses like EC were a tricky one for me. I liked the key takeaways from this course, but I hated the fact that it was a 25 session course - the core ideas were discussed in 4 sessions, and the rest was just reiteration using different cases. Nonetheless, the framework Saral da provides for Operations (and Business) Strategy through this course was unique!</p> <p><em><strong>Key Takeaway:</strong></em></p> <p>A competitive business environment is similar to a jungle, and every firm is a living system in itself consisting of different subsystems. You can classify firms on various dimensions of Operations Strategy as Elephants, Cheetahs, Insects, etc. Strategy is the art of closing doors. When a business chooses a strategy, ensure that all its subcomponents choose the same strategy, else that company will not survive.</p> <hr/> <p><strong>Monetizing Artificial Intelligence and Technology by Prof. Anuj Kapoor</strong></p> <p>This was the only Marketing course I took in my second year. I’m not going to lie - I went into this course because Marketing Area courses have a penchant for easy grading. <em><strong>BUT BOY, WAS THIS COURSE AN ABSOLUTE DELIGHT!</strong></em></p> <p>As someone who loves the startup world, this was the course that I felt came closest to relatability in terms of what is going on in the real world. One of the fantastic things about the course is the guest lecturers who are industry stalwarts like Anand Daniel from Accel, Movin Jain from PhonePe, and Ashray Malhotra from Rephrase.ai.</p> <p><em><strong>Key Takeaway:</strong></em></p> <p>State-of-the-art technology means nothing in a business if you can’t monetize it properly. Have a mental framework for monetizing any AI technology and ensure that the change in customer value that you unlock through technology is much more than the cost of developing it.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="education"/><category term="career"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s nearly 3 AM in the night, and I’m at Vikram Sarabhai Library because the heat in the old campus is getting intolerable. As I enter the last week or so in my MBA journey, I think it’s an excellent time to take a step back and look at the bigger picture.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Investment Philosophies</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/13/ashutosh-jha-investment-philosophies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Investment Philosophies"/><published>2022-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/13/ashutosh-jha-investment-philosophies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/13/ashutosh-jha-investment-philosophies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last 4 years in my Financial Markets journey, I’ve had the fortune to observe different ways in which people have made really good returns.</p> <p>The interesting thing about all these people is in the psychology and the way they’ve chosen to invest — and here’s the punchline, <em><strong>there is no one single “do this and you’ll get results” way of making money in the markets</strong></em>.</p> <p>What was however common amongst all these people was the temparement with which they chose to invest money. <em><strong>All of them had a unique overarching belief in the way markets worked and they stuck to that belief regardless of what was “hot” in the markets today.</strong></em> So much so that they stuck to it for decades at a go.</p> <p>I’ll make an attempt to showcase two of the worlds I’ve been a part of. While they may appear different prima facie, people in both worlds are just taking different approaches in extracting the same returns from Market Inefficiencies.</p> <p><strong>The World of Quants</strong></p> <p>When I first got a taste of financial markets, it was through the lens of being a Quant on a trading floor. For those of you who do not know what a Quant does, a one liner to it is that we make complex mathematical models to find the “true” price of a financial asset (might be a stock, a derivative, or a currency) and use that to take bets on the market — either betting that the price of the asset would go up or it would go down depending on the current market price and the price that I get from my model.</p> \[\begin{align*} &amp;C = N(d_1)S_t - N(d_2)Ke^{-rt} \\\\ &amp;\text{where } d_1 = \frac{\ln \frac{S_t}{K} + (r + \frac{\sigma^2}{2})t}{\sigma \sqrt{t}} \\\\ &amp;\text{and } d_2 = d_1 - \sigma \sqrt{t} \end{align*}\] <p>An example of a mathematical model is the Black Scholes Model which gives us the price of a derivative called an Option</p> <p>The interesting thing about the world of quants is that they very rarely tend to focus on the underlying business of a financial asset. They rather just focus on the historical prices of the asset and believe that there is an ability to predict (forecast) the future from the historical prices.</p> <p><em><strong>In the world of quants, you stringently develop a strong robust mathematical model based on historical prices and put all your faith in the model to predict the future.</strong></em></p> <p><strong>The World of Fundamentals</strong></p> <p>The world of what are called fundamental investors (or <strong>value investors</strong> ) have been popularized by Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger through their extremely strong record at Berkshire Hathaway.</p> <p>Fundamentals based investing can be broken down into three simple tenets:</p> <ol> <li> <p><em><strong>Remembering that stocks are businesses</strong></em><br/> Every stock is ultimately a piece of the underlying business itself and gets its value from how good or bad the underlying business is. A “good” business should be valued higher than a “bad” business. There is hence an intrinsic value to every stock which may or may not be equal to its market price.</p> </li> <li> <p><em><strong>Think in terms of Mr. Market</strong></em><br/> Value investors think of the broader stock market in terms of a drunk overenthusiastic man (“Mr. Market”) who at times is sane and is ready to buy or sell the stock at a reasonable price similar to what its intrinsic value is. At times Mr. Market has had too much to drink and he will quote you prices which are way out of whack from the intrinsic value. <br/> Do not worry when Mr. Market does that — he will get sober over time and bring the prices back to normal. But while he’s at it, you might be able to get a good bet to make either going long the stock or short the stock.</p> </li> <li> <p><em><strong>Always build in a Margin of Safety</strong></em><br/> There are always risks in understanding the true value of a business — unlike hard sciences, social sciences are a messy world. There are so many things that could go wrong: you trust the management of a business to do right but they turn out crooks, customer preferences for a product might just change (who uses Blackberry Phones anymore!).<br/> Since the world we live in is messy, when trying to value a business, always bake in a margin of safety — hence there is no one true intrinsic value per se, but a range of values which are reasonable. Buy or sell a stock only when it goes outside that range.</p> </li> </ol> <p><em><strong>In the world of fundamental investors, stocks are businesses with a range of reasonable intrinsic values and you buy or sell when the market is too irrational about a stock.</strong></em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="investing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last 4 years in my Financial Markets journey, I’ve had the fortune to observe different ways in which people have made really good returns.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Curiously Clueless!</title><link href="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/03/ashutosh-jha-welcome-to-curiously-clueless.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Curiously Clueless!"/><published>2022-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/03/ashutosh-jha-welcome-to-curiously-clueless</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jhashut.github.io/2022/02/03/ashutosh-jha-welcome-to-curiously-clueless.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello there!</p> <p><strong>This is Curiously Clueless</strong> , a newsletter about Thoughts of a clueless but curious human.</p> <p>I’ll use this newsletter mostly to cover my thoughts and learnings in the areas of Investing, Financial Markets, and Technology for most part.</p> <p>One of the first advices I was given was:</p> <blockquote> <p><em>Better to remain silent and be thought a fool than to speak and to remove all doubt</em></p> </blockquote> <p>My one simple goal through this newsletter is to go <strong>against</strong> this advice and make very public mistakes to learn from them. The self-indulging of my ego is just a side benefit!</p> <p>Cheers,<br/> A</p>]]></content><author><name>Ashutosh Jha</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello there!]]></summary></entry></feed>